SILE KIMAN

Charlotte, NC · Phone: 980-339-2136 Email: sile.kiman@yahoo.com

PROFILE:

Senior Quality Assurance Analyst with over 10 years of progressive advancement in the Information Technology field. Specialized experience in manual and automation testing. Demonstrated hands-on skills with mobile and web application testing. In-depth knowledge of SDLC, Agile and Waterfall Methodologies. Take initiative to work on challenging and "stretch" work assignments. Strong analytical skills and ability to multitask and quickly adjust to people, circumstances and responsibilities.

EXPERIENCE

Contract Matlen Silver/Bank Of America
Senior QA Analyst (Mobile Web and Web testing)

Feb 2018- Current

- Set testing processes and procedures for other testers and ensure myself and others' adherence to enterprise testing standards, frameworks, and controls.
- Perform manual and automated testing in Agile SDLC using an in house Selenium and Java based framework called Autogen.
- Work in Agile scrum teams alongside Development, Business Analyst and Feature Leads to build and maintain effective testing strategies.
- Plan and Execute Test Scripts using Rally to Track and Log bugs.
- Perform cross bowser testing using Sauce Lab.
- Attend daily Scrum meetings to update the team and discuss any impediments holding up testing progress.
- Perform Web testing and use iOS and Android devices to do Mobile Web and ADA testing for the BOA Store Front and Online Applications
- Conduct functional, integrated and performance testing ,end-to-end and regression testing on applications and technology, to make sure that business, technical and functional requirements are being met throughout the SDLC.
- Execute test scripts based upon test strategy/plans in an effort to identify defects prior to production.
- Send a Production certification on release day which requires manual/automated scripts be executed

Environnent: Rally, Autogen, Sauce Lab, iOS, Android, Lync communication.

Contract Ettain Group/Lowes Iris Smart Home Senior QA Engineer (Mobile, Web service & Platform testing)

May 2018- Feb 2019

- Lead ENT Mobile Application testing on Android and iOS devices.
- Worked in Agile scrum teams alongside Development, Platform, Business Analyst and Scrum Master to build and maintain effective testing strategies.
- Performed backend testing on Web API calls using Java-based internal GUI tool to validate communications between devices and the Platform.
- Plan and Execute Test Cases using TestRail, and JIRA to Track and Log bug.
- Attended daily Scrum meetings to update the team and discuss any impediments holding up testing progress.
- Uses iOS and Android devices to test the Iris App UI design and functional Integration testing of all new features.
- Performed Web, Mobile and Platform regression testing of the Iris Smart Home applications
- Performed devices Firmware upgrade and downgrade to meet well functioning state of the devices.
- Tested connectivity protocol and physical state of each devices such as WI-FI Camera, Contact Sensors and Motions sensor.
- Worked on home security, home automation products and device integrations such as Z-wave, Zigbee, Lutron, Alexa, Home kit devices
- Environment: JSON, Java, JIRA, TestRail, Citrix, iOS, Android, Smart Home devices Lab., Oculus (Java-based internal GUI tool for API call), Confluence, Slack.
- Devices: Smart Hub, Indoor & Outdoor Camera, Contact Sensor, Motion Sensor, Indoor & Outdoor Wi-Fi Smart plugs, Door Locks.

The Newport Group Charlotte, NC Senior QA Analyst (Mobile and Web Applications Testing.)

Dec 2013 – May 2018

- Performed Mobile testing using physical devices (iOS, Android and Tablets)
- Worked in Agile scrum teams alongside development and business analysts to build and maintain effective testing strategies.
- Developed and test Automation test scripts using Selenium Web driver with Python in Robot and Pytest Automation Framework.
- Enhanced existed framework.
- Automated manual test cases for Regression testing.
- Integrated automation test scripts with Jenkins, TFS for continuous integration and test suite run.

- Performed manual Functional and Regression testing in multiple Environments on Web based applications as well as mobile Apps that allow consumers to manage their Retirement plans activities such as Loan request, Re-allocations of investments and Distributions Request.
- Created Test plans, Design Test Cases and Perform Peer Reviews.
- Set up testing environment and Test Data (e.g. Creating Enrollments or Uploading Data) before executing test cases or start testing.
- Executed Test Cases using Quality Center, and TFS, Track and Log Defect/bug, attend defect triage meetings or stand-ups to provide status for logged defects.
- Executed basic SQL queries to verify/validate data.
- Performed web application security screening, testing and reporting.

Environment: Python, Selenium web driver, TFS, AML, Windows7, Eclipse, GitHub, firebug, fire path, PyCharm, Eclipse.

Ally Financial, Charlotte, NC Senior QA Analyst (eCommerce-Mobile and Web Application Testing) July 2012- Dec 2013

- Performed user acceptance testing in eCommerce environment for both US and French-Canadian applications
- Tested Mobile Applications on iOS and Android operating Systems Using Device Anywhere and physical devices
- Created test cases to validate End-to-End test scenarios.
- Collected, analyzed and validated test data
- Executed test cases, documented and reported defects using Quality Center.
- Experience with various types of testing (integration, Regression, and user acceptance)
- Involved in the day-to-day tasks of the user acceptance testing process including triage meeting to discuss defects related issues.
- Experienced with all types of major system development and deployment projects
- Applied skills and knowledge acquired through training and/or documentation
- Performed and lead processes related to testing activities for new software systems
- Developed and executed formal test plans to ensure the delivery of quality software applications.
- Served as mentor for junior test analysts and provide direction to others in the project
- Worked independently to define, manage, and complete activities

Environment: SQL, QC, Windows 2000, XP, Citrix, Device Anywhere, Android, iOS

Connextions, Inc., Concord, NC Technical/QA Analyst

Sep 2008- July 2012

- Performed Business Requirements Analysis for product enhancement projects
- Developed and executed test cases using Quality Center
- Developed test plans and test strategies for various testing activities
- Provided analysis and summary of defects during defects review meetings

- Participated and provided feedback to team members during peer-review meetings
- Performed testing on VoIP phone adapters and call routing systems.
- Effectively troubleshot problems with Small Office / Home Office (SOHO) configurations, TCP/IP, DNS, Firewalls, VOIP, routers, switches, hubs, and Cable/DSL modems.
- Extensively tested and evaluated the capabilities of end-user hardware in regard to ensuring high-quality voice over IP calls.
- Documented and provided feedback on overall device quality and usability;
- Researched and analyzed end-user network configurations in order to make recommendations on best practices for maximizing voice quality of service;
- Collaborated with peers, Product Development, and Account Managers to resolve client issues.
- Followed proper procedures for accurate and timely documentation of issues
- Provided Subject Matter Expert (SME) level support to colleagues

Environment: SQL, Java, QC, Windows 2000, XP, HTML, Remedy, debugging tool, VoIP adapter.

EDUCATION / TRAINING / CERTIFICATE:

Bellevue University, Nebraska 2007
Bachelor's Degree, Computer Information Systems
Java Programming Language Training Certificate 2007
UNCC Charlotte April 2020
Coding BootCamp: Front-End & Back End development

TECHNICAL SKILLS/TOOLS:

Testing Tools: JIRA, TestRail, AML, UFT, Citrix, Device Anywhere, BURP, BI Launch PAD, TFS, Selenium Web driver, Robot Framework, Oculus.

Devices: iOS, Android, Indoor & Outdoor Camera, Contact Sensor, Motion Sensor, Indoor & Outdoor Wi-Fi Smart plugs Door Locks, VoIP Phone Adaptor.

Languages: JavaScript, JQuery, **Database:** MySQL, SQL Server 2008

Operating Systems: Windows XP/2000, Windows Vista, 7,

Office Tools: Microsoft Excel, Access, Visio, PowerPoint, Project, Outlook, Snaglt, Team Viewer,

Microsoft Lync Communicator, WebEx, Shortel, SharePoint, Slack.

Web Tech: HTML5 CSS/Bootstrap